JOSEPH FRAMBACH

joe@framba.ch; (412) 865-7790

I've worked in transportation/logistics, event ticketing, mortgage, and personal finance. It's a big world out there, so what's next? Healthcare is growing. Autonomous vehicles are moving. Smart appliances are getting smarter. Internationalization is connecting people. Where do I see myself in five years? Who knows! Let's find out!

EXPERIENCE

NerdWallet

May 2015 to April 2016

Senior Frontend Engineer

- · **Credit Card Tool**: Reusable react components for redesign of credit card comparison tool.
- · **Small Business and Personal Loans**: Onboarding and filtering interface.
- · **Wordpress Shortcode UI**: Simple interface for content managers to edit blog mini-templates.
- · **React Component Guide**: Shareable, hackable library of atomic react components.
- **Optisizely**: A visualization of how Optimizely tests affect page weight.
- · **Reading Group**: The Innovator's Dilemma; team size and autonomy in hackathon projects.
- · **On The Ball**: Stay on top of your finances through life milestones.

Trulia

September 2013 to May 2015

Senior Software Engineer

Full-stack developer on a small "New Ventures" team, exploring possibilities in mortgage search and streamlining the home buying process. Building and maintaining desktop, mobile, and API.

- · **Zillow integration**: Post-merger data and widget sharing across very different systems.
- · **Investment calculator**: Tools to decide between selling your home and becoming a landlord.
- · **mWeb**: Node, Rendr, and Backbone isomorphic mobile site.
- \cdot $\mbox{\bf Pre-approval short form:}$ Connect highly qualified leads to mortgage lenders.
- · **Mortgage rate table**: Affordability estimation and lender matching for home seekers.
- · **User preferences**: Store arbitrary user preferences from input throughout the site.
- · Lender rotation: Fairly distribute leads to several mortgage lenders.
- · **Co-registration**: Extensible framework to upsell simultaneous third-party leads.
- · **Review moderation**: Hold, archive, and accept user-generated reviews.
- **Independent projects**: PHP HBase bindings; Collaborative git conflict editor; Satis Composer repository.

Senior Software Engineer

Ticketing software for event organizers, and front-end checkout for customers. Lead architect and developer for core administrative features:

- · **Incentix**: Use Facebook and Twitter API to give discounts with social promotion.
- **Embed & Facebook checkout**: Embeds ShowClix into client website or Facebook page tab.
- · **Merchandising**: Product selling and fulfillment platform used by C2E2 and Blue October.
- **Product bundles**: Groups tickets and merchandise, with flexible pricing and reporting options.
- · **Membership**: Offers members-only tickets and discounts with client's external API.
- · **Self-serve membership**: Sellers may import membership lists into ShowClix-hosted MongoDB.
- · **Questions**: Sellers may ask questions to customers per-sale, per-event, and per-ticket.
- · **Order fulfillment**: Queues shippable orders, verifies tickets, and tracks shipping to customers.
- **BOCA thermal printing**: Prints physical tickets using a BOCA printer, with collation options.
- · Email Outbox: Sellers may draft and send emails to customers using TinyMCE editor.
- **Stress testing**: Uses Grinder and Linode API to replicate production and slam it with 50,000 users.
- · **Local meetups**: Assist in hosting local node.js meetups, and social recruiting event, Engibeering.

United States Steel Corporation

May 2006 to June 2010

Business Services - Warehouse, Shipping, and Logistics

- · Automated PDF report generation for inventory management and scheduling.
- · Automated PDF generation for bills of lading, truck freight paperwork, and internal mill needs.
- $\cdot \ Converted \ main frame \ COBOL/AS400 \ programs \ into \ VB.NET \ web \ interfaces.$
- \cdot Supported older ASP and J2EE applications for multiple teams.

EDUCATION

University of Pittsburgh

Spring 2008

B.S., Applied Mathematics and Computer Science with Honors

- · Mathematics in Industry: Explored methods for shape recognition and classification, for searching a database of shapes.
- · Carnegie Mellon University Question-Answering System Competition: Used NLP to analyze

text sources, generate and answer questions.

· "CS Day" Poster Competition: Explained iterative methods for finding approximate solutions of systems of nonlinear equations.

University of Pittsburgh

Fall 2008 - Spring 2012

M.S., Computer Science (Incomplete)

· Graduate coursework

Operating Systems, Machine Learning, Compiler Design, Data Modeling and Visualization, Wide Area Networks, Human-Computer Interface Design and Evaluation, Algorithm Design.

· Projects

Human-Computer Interfaces: Designed and built Arduino theremin using light sensor.

Data Visualization and Modeling: Used Ruby on Rails and flot to show inter-hospital MRSA levels.

INTERESTS

· Backpacked 2,100 miles of the Pacific Crest Trail.

Summer 2016

· General Assembly inteview practice volunteer.

Spring 2016

· Toastmasters communication and leadership development, member.

May 2014 - Present

- · Stripe Capture the Flag.
 - v3.0 Networking challenges: Distributed computing, Denial of Service.

Aug 2013

- v2.0 Web challenges: SQL injection, CSRF vulnerabilies, SHA1 padding.

Aug 2012

· Backpacked the Appalachian Trail from Georgia to Maine.

Summer 2008

- · Ran marathons in Chicago, Pikes Peak, Virginia Beach, Philadelphia, and Pittsburgh.
- · Bicycled from Pittsburgh to Washington, DC, and Pittsburgh to Lake Erie.
- · TIME Magazine: Person of the Year

2006

"We're looking at an explosion of productivity and innovation, and it's just getting started."

· Boy Scouts of America: Eagle Scout Rank

January 2004

- Designed and built a 30-foot timber bridge which withstood Hurricane Ivan.